ADNAN VALDES

Summary

Enthusiastic and dedicated Data Scientist with a wide range of experience in developing and translating varied, complex knowledge domains into user-friendly forms. 10 years of experience in commercial flight operations and flight instruction, a degree in history, and a wide cultural background; systems thinker, a curious explorer, and a passionate learner.

Employment

Pacific Coastal Airlines

Jul. 2018 - Mar. 2020 Vancouver, BC

First Officer

- Operated Saab 340 aircraft in multi-crew environments

- Audited company training records to ensure Transport Canada and ICAO compliance.
- Developed and fine-tuned resource management skills and teamwork abilities.

Pacific Flying Club

Jul. 2016 - Dec. 2019

Vancouver, BC

Flight Instructor

- Taught theory classes as well as practical flying lessons.
- Upgraded to and managed courses for multi-engine and advanced instrument flight operations.
- Trained candidates for interviews, both in theory reviews and in advanced simulator sessions.

Projects

3380 Books

Nov. 2020 - Dec. 2020

A book database search engine that is able to parse reviews for books and create thematic clusters to reduce the time spent to get at the heart of a book before reading it.

Built with Tensorflow's Universal Sentence Encoder, NLTK, Gensim, Sklearn', and Streamlit. Created from the UCSD Book Graph dataset.

Waypoint Aviation Connections

Jul. 2015 - Nov. 2017

Co-Founder and corporate relations director for the first networking event organized by the students of Vancouver's universities for those interested in pursuing a career in the aviation industry.

The attending companies included some of the best-recognized airlines in the country, as well as numerous local firms and government organizations.

Volunteering

UBC Aviation Club

President

Sep. 2012 - Nov. 2015 Vancouver, BC

Managed day-today activities as well as promoting long-term member engagement with the aviation industry. Doubled active membership in the club, organized aviation facility tours, and created the first student-led aviation theory classes at UBC.

Aviation Leadership Foundation

Mar. 2017 - Sep. 2018

Event Coordinator

Vancouver, BC

Helped organize the aviation leadership foundation's yearly event.

Awards

Outstanding International Student Sep. 2012

University of British Columbia

Sep. 2011

Trek Excellence Scholarship University of British Columbia **COVID-19 Relief Scholarship**

Flight Instructor Scholarship

Lighthouse Labs

Aug. 2020

Jul. 2016

BC Aviation Council

Contact

■ adravaldes@gmail.com

adnanvaldes.com

Richmond, BC

in adnanvaldes

AdnanValdes

Education

Lighthouse Labs

Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2020 Diploma Data Science

Pacific Flying Club

Aug. 2012 - Nov. 2016 Commercial Pilot's License

University of British Columbia

Sep. 2011 - Nov. 2015 **BA** History

Skills

Teaching

Curriculum development Presentation methods

Public speaking

Communication

Machine Learning

Scikit-Learn

Tensorflow

NLTK

Gensim

Pandas

spaCy

Programming

Python

SQL

Platforms AWS

Flask

Streamlit

Docker

ngrok

Languages

English

Spanish